loxone.com 2018-09-04

# Data Protection Statement - Loxone Smart Home Automation UK

### 1\. DATA CONTROLLER

Loxone Electronics GmbH, Smart Home 1, 4154 Kollerschlag, Austria (office@loxone.com) is the office responsible for the collection, processing and use of your personal data.

If you wish to lodge a complaint concerning the collection, processing or use of your data by Loxone, whether relating to the regulations for data protection generally or to more specific cases, this can be done by email, fax or by post. Your personal data will then be deleted, provided that no legal obligation exists to keep them if you have made a valid cancellation claim, if the data are no longer necessary for achieving a target which constitutes the aim of the data storage itself, or if the storage of your data is otherwise legally inadmissible.

### 2\. COLLECTION, PROCESSING AND USE OF PERSONAL DATA

#### 2.1 Personal Data

Personal data are details concerning factual or personal conditions pertaining to an identified or identifiable physical person. This includes, for example, your name, your telephone number, your signature, as well as numerous inventory data which you share with us upon opening a customer account with us.

#### 2.2 Customer Account

In order to shop with us, you require a customer account. This customer account comprises personal data. These are stored in our data bank for later processing when logging in.

#### 2.3 Collection, processing and use of your personal data

Data protection is an important concern for us. Therefore, when collecting, processing and using your personal data, we strictly adhere to the legal provisions of the General Data Protection Regulation _[Bestimmungen der Datenschutz-Grundverordnung]_ ( GDPR _[DSGVO]_ ) and the Telecommunications Act _[Telekommunikationsgesetzes]_ (TKG).

We comply with the principle that data collection is for a specific purpose and collect, process and store your personal data only for the smooth completion of your purchase, potentially including later guarantees for our services department, technical administration as well as our own marketing goals. Your personal data are only forwarded to third parties or otherwise given over if this is necessary to the completion of the contract or the invoice or upon your prior consent. In the context of order processing, the service providers we use (e.g. suppliers) receive the necessary data. The forwarded data may only be used by our service providers in order to perform their task. Any other use of this information is not permissible and would not occur with any of the service providers appointed by us.

For your order, we require your correct name, address and payment details.  We require your email address in order to confirm the receipt of your order with you and in order to communicate with you. Moreover, we use this for your identification (customer log-in). We also take data protection within the company most seriously. Our colleagues and our appointed service providers (e.g. suppliers) are bound to secrecy and adherence to the terms of the data protection law.

#### 2.4 Use of your data for advertising purposes

Alongside the processing of your data in order to complete your purchase with Loxone, we also use them in order to communicate with you regarding your order, certain products or marketing campaigns and in order to recommend products or services to you, which could be of interest.

You can always object to the use of your personal data for advertising purposes, whether in general or pertaining to individual cases. This can be done by contacting us in any way mentioned under point 1 (e.g. email, letter).

2.5 Infomail/Newsletters

In order to send our infomail/newsletters we operate a so-called double opt-in process. This means we will only send you our infomail/newsletters by email if you have previously expressly confirmed that we should activate our infomail/newsletters service. We will then send you a notification email and ask you to confirm that you wish to receive our infomails/newsletters by clicking one of the links provided in this email. If you later no longer wish to receive infomails/newsletters from us, you can always cancel this subscription. This can be done by contacting us in any of the ways mentioned in point 1. Of course, you will also find an unsubscribe link in each infomail.

#### 2.6 Social Media Marketing

The Loxone website uses the Facebook Pixel and other such cookie-like tags. We might use these tags to serve specific ad content to you – for example on Facebook and it’s Audience Network – based on your browsing behaviour only on the Loxone website. We may also use this Pixel and such technologies to record some actions you take on our website, such as completing a contact form or reaching the checkout stage of our webshop. The Facebook Pixel does not pass any of your personal information to Loxone. We cannot identify who you are based on the actions of such tags. Using the likes of _Custom Audiences_ on Facebook, we might include or exclude users with your browsing behaviour in targetted or remarketing ad campaigns. You have full control of your privacy settings on Facebook. You can learn more about what influences the ads you see by [clicking here](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product=ad_settings_screen).

The behaviour recorded on our website via such tags may be used by the services we advertise through, to determine a lookalike audience. As above, this audience may be included or excluded from Loxone ad campaigns. Therefore, your non-identifying characteristics may inform the persons included in lookalike audiences. This is in no way managed by Loxone and the information used in the determining of or creating of such an audience is not in our possession nor do we have access to it. Read more information by [clicking here](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/164749007013531?helpref=related&ref=related#).

We use Facebook Ads for general marketing. As outlined above, this may be based on the information we hold on you or based on the information Facebook holds on you. You can find out more about this advertising medium by [clicking here](https://www.facebook.com/about/ads/).

### 3\. USE OF COOKIES

Cookies are used on the website at www.loxone.com These are small text files that your browser stores on your device. You can control the use of cookies in your browser settings (e.g. prevent the use of cookies or delete cookies). Please read the instructions from your browser or device manufacturer. The cookies used here are used to make the website more user-friendly. Please note that if you object to the use of cookies, you may not be able to use all functions of the website in full.

We currently use cookies for Google Analytics and Zoho Corporation’s CRM. Furthermore, so-called session cookies are used, which are necessary for the functionality of our services and are only stored for the duration of the visit.

### 4\. GOOGLE ANALYTICS

In order constantly to improve and optimise our offers, we use Google Analytics as a tracking technology.

Google Analytics uses cookies, which are stored on your browser and enable an analysis of the use of our website. The information generated by the cookies about how you access and use our website, including your IP address, is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there.

You can prevent Google from collecting data generated by cookies by clicking the link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=install> and installing the available browser plugin.

We have concluded a corresponding contract with Google for the processing of your data.

### 5\. ZOHO

Zoho uses cookies which are stored on your browser and enable an analysis of the use of our website. The information generated by the cookies about how you access and use our website, including your IP address, is transferred to a Zoho server in the USA and stored there.

Zoho Corporation participates in the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/) and certifies its compliance. Zoho Corporation undertakes to comply with the Privacy Shield Agreement and all personal data received from member states of the European Union (EU) in accordance with the applicable procedures of the Agreement. Further information on the Privacy Shield can be found on the Privacy Shield List of the US Chamber of Commerce, available at [https://www.privacyshield.gov/list](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

We have concluded a corresponding contract with Zoho Corporation for the processing of your data.

### 6\. SECURE DATA TRANSFER

Your personal data are put into code by digital security systems and transferred to us. Our website is protected by technical measures against damages, destruction or unauthorised access.

### 7\. YOUR RIGHTS

In principle, you have the right to information, correction, deletion, restriction, data transferability, revocation and objection. If you believe that the processing of your data violates data protection law or your data protection claims have otherwise been violated in any way, you can complain to the supervisory authority. Loxone Electronics GmbH, Falkensteinstraße 6, 4154 Kollerschlag (office@loxone.com) is the office responsible for the collection, processing and use of your personal data. Therefore, in Austria, the supervisory authority is [Datenschutzbehörde](https://www.dsb.gv.at/).

### 8\. CHANGES TO THIS DATA PROTECTION STATEMENT

We reserve the right to amend this data protection statement. You can always find the current valid version at this link: <https://www.loxone.com/enen/info/data-protection-statement/> .
